london.ac.uk 2018-04-25

# Privacy policy and cookies | University of London

## Privacy Statement

When you supply any personal information to the University of London we have legal obligations towards you in the way we deal with that data. We must collect the information fairly, that is, we must explain how we will use it and tell you if we want to pass the information on to anyone else. In general, any information you provide to the University of London will only be used within the University of London and by its service providers. It will never be supplied to anyone outside the University of London without first obtaining your consent, unless we are obliged or permitted by law to disclose it. This applies to your name, email addresses, personal information and any email correspondence. Also, if you post or send offensive or inappropriate content anywhere on or to the University of London or otherwise engage in any disruptive behaviour on the University of London website, and the University of London considers such behaviour to be serious and/or repeated, the University of London can use whatever information that is available to it about you to stop such behaviour. This may include informing relevant third parties such as your employer, college or email provider about the content and your behaviour.

We will hold your personal information on our systems for as long as you use the service you have requested, and remove it in the event that the purpose has been met. Where personal information is held for people who are not yet registered but have taken part in other services (for example, competitions), that information will be held only as long as necessary to ensure that the service is run smoothly. We will ensure that all personal information supplied is held securely, in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998.

If you are notified on the University of London website that your information may be used to allow the University of London to contact you for 'service administration purposes', this means that the University of London may contact you for a number of purposes related to the service you have signed up for. For example, we may wish to provide you with password reminders or notify you that the particular service has been suspended for maintenance. We will not contact you for promotional purposes, such as notifying you of improvements to the service or new services on the University of London website unless you specifically agree to be contacted for such purposes at the time you submit your information on the website, or at a later time if you sign up specifically to receive such information.

Development office data protection statement

## Cookies

There are various instances where we use cookies, e.g. for website analytics, and other instances where it requires the use of cookies for functionality and authentication purposes, e.g. in the online application process and for access to the student portal.

We also use cookies to deliver targeted advertising based on your use of our site and to measure the performance of our advertising. Information about this and your options for opting out of advertising cookies is available from the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/#!/). Alternatively, consult the documentation for your web browser or mobile device for further options to control which cookies you allow. Advertising technologies which may set cookies on this site include (but are not limited to) AdWords, DoubleClick, and social media platforms (including Facebook, Twitter, and others).

If you have access to the student portal and/or a VLE, then please read the statements relevant to these systems on the portal or VLE.

## Web Forms

Where web forms are utilised on this website you are usually required to supply some sort of personal information; this might only be a reply email address, however, elsewhere considerably more detailed information may be required, e.g. in the online application process. In general, forms on the University of London website will either contain an explanation about how the information you supply will be used or will provide a link to this page.

## Data Protection

The information you provide to the University of London will be processed in accordance with the provisions of the Data Protection Act (1998) and any other relevant legislation. This data may be used to provide you with further information about relevant services. It may be held on a mailing list or database for this purpose, unless you object (by notifying the University in writing); and it may also be passed on to a third-party (a 'data processor') with whom the University has formally contracted to process your data for this purpose, subject to the safeguards concerning privacy and security of data set out in the Act.

## Student / social Network(s)

In certain instances the University of London website facilitates communication between students (and staff) via online networks. The networks primarily operate on an 'opt-in' basis, i.e. you have to request that your details are added to the network and consent to their inclusion. The views expressed by students using these networks (or similar) do not reflect the views of the University of London.

The University of London uses Sprout Social as our Social Media Management tool. Their privacy statement can be found on their website via the following link: <http://sproutsocial.com/privacy-policy>

If you have access to the Student Portal and/or a VLE, then please read the statements relevant to these systems.

## Google analytics

The University of London website uses Google Analytics to collecting information on how visitors use our site. This information is used to create reporting and analysis to allow us to improve the site for our users. The cookies used by Google Analytics collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.

We use Google Analytics to collect Demographics and Interests data, which is anonymised information based on Google's record of your browsing across the web. This data is limited to Google's estimation of your age bracket, gender, and interests. By continuing your navigation of this site, you are consenting to the University collecting and using your information for the purposes stated above

You can disable Google Analytics tracking on your browser by following the [instructions](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en) on the Google site.
